<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xtra on gi-modules</title>
    <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/categories/xtra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xtra on gi-modules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us^</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/categories/xtra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About GI-Modules</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-15-howto-gi-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-15-howto-gi-modules/</guid>
      <description>Concept GI Modules is a blog-based collection of learning content in the broad field of geoinformatics. The blogs are sorted by categories and tags. Under the categories, related content is grouped together. Within the content pages, you can navigate to related articles via the tags.
The contents are therefore thematically associated but not intended as a closed workflow. The course units are composed of individual modules.
Currently the following course contents are integrated:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Learning environment</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-learning-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-learning-environment/</guid>
      <description>Web-based learning environment Your primary learning environment is this publicly accessible homepage we create on GitHub. Here you will find learning materials, tasks, and support. Open questions can be asked at any time during the course or via comments/email. All questions will be discussed in a screencast or online (FAQ).
Flexible learning with fixed deadlines The course schedule provides for a two-to four hour block. These events weíll be offered in classroom and as possible as live stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Assignments</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-assignments/</guid>
      <description>To start with, get yourself a GitHub account if you have not one already and create your learning log repository. Be aware that once the learning log repository is created, you will stick to this until the end of the course.
Once you have a GitHub account, you can create as many repositories as you like at your account and invite any team members you want. Within this course you will submit your solutions for the course assignments to a private GitHub-hosted learning log, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-21-impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-21-impressum/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Framework This course is brought with the background of Open Educational Resources initiative coordinated by the Leibniz-Institut für Bildungsforschung und Bildungsinformation and integrated in the official teaching framework of the Marburg University, Germany. It is developed at the Department of Geography under responsibility of the gisma-courses site.
Content Responsibility The responsibility for the content rests with the instructors. Statements, opinions and/or conclusions are the ones from the instructors and do not necessarily reflect the opinion of the representatives of Marburg University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2022-06-23-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2022-06-23-test/</guid>
      <description>Stackoverflow question https://stackoverflow.com/questions/45360998/code-folding-in-bookdown
# Add a common class name for every chunks knitr::opts_chunk$set( echo = TRUE) codejs &amp;lt;- readr::read_lines(&amp;#34;js/codefolding.js&amp;#34;) collapsejs &amp;lt;- readr::read_lines(&amp;#34;js/collapse.js&amp;#34;) transitionjs &amp;lt;- readr::read_lines(&amp;#34;js/transition.js&amp;#34;) htmlhead &amp;lt;- paste(&amp;#39; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&amp;#39;, paste(transitionjs, collapse = &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;), &amp;#39;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&amp;#39;, paste(collapsejs, collapse = &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;), &amp;#39;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&amp;#39;, paste(codejs, collapse = &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;), &amp;#39;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;style type=&amp;#34;text/css&amp;#34;&amp;gt; .code-folding-btn { margin-bottom: 4px; } .row { display: flex; } .collapse { display: none; } .in { display:block } &amp;lt;/style&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; $(document).ready(function () { window.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
