<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on gi-modules</title>
    <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on gi-modules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us^</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About GI-Modules</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-15-howto-gi-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-15-howto-gi-modules/</guid>
      <description>Concept GI Modules is a blog-based collection of learning content in the broad field of geoinformatics. The blogs are sorted by categories and tags. Under the categories, related content is grouped together. Within the content pages, you can navigate to related articles via the tags.
The contents are therefore thematically associated but not intended as a closed workflow. The course units are composed of individual modules.
Currently the following course contents are integrated:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Learning environment</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-learning-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-learning-environment/</guid>
      <description>Web-based learning environment Your primary learning environment is this publicly accessible homepage we create on GitHub. Here you will find learning materials, tasks, and support. Open questions can be asked at any time during the course or via comments/email. All questions will be discussed in a screencast or online (FAQ).
Flexible learning with fixed deadlines The course schedule provides for a two-to four hour block. These events weíll be offered in classroom and as possible as live stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Assignments</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-assignments/</guid>
      <description>To start with, get yourself a GitHub account if you have not one already and create your learning log repository. Be aware that once the learning log repository is created, you will stick to this until the end of the course.
Once you have a GitHub account, you can create as many repositories as you like at your account and invite any team members you want. Within this course you will submit your solutions for the course assignments to a private GitHub-hosted learning log, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-21-impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-21-impressum/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Framework This course is brought with the background of Open Educational Resources initiative coordinated by the Leibniz-Institut für Bildungsforschung und Bildungsinformation and integrated in the official teaching framework of the Marburg University, Germany. It is developed at the Department of Geography under responsibility of the gisma-courses site.
Content Responsibility The responsibility for the content rests with the instructors. Statements, opinions and/or conclusions are the ones from the instructors and do not necessarily reflect the opinion of the representatives of Marburg University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-Oriented Workflow</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-project-oriented-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-project-oriented-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Flexible but reproducible setup To set up a working or project environment, (normally) the first steps are defining different folder paths and loading the necessary R packages as well as additional functions.
If you also need to access additional software, like GIS, the appropriate binaries and software environments must be linked, too. Factoring in the major operating systems and the potentially multiple versions of software installed on a single system results in almost unlimited combinations of set ups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic writing made easy</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-making-of-academic-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-making-of-academic-websites/</guid>
      <description>Setting up the blogdown Project We will use blogdown as an incredible easy to use an effiecient tool for setting up websites and producing content. First you need to install the neccessary packages:
# Install blogdown  install.packages(&amp;#34;blogdown&amp;#34;) # Install the &amp;#34;hugo&amp;#34; website framework blogdown::install_hugo(force = TRUE) library(blogdown) To initialize a blogdown website I strongly recommend to use the menu bar of RStudio.
 RStudio toolbar -&amp;gt; File -&amp;gt; New Project -&amp;gt; New Directory -&amp;gt; blogdown website Copy gisma-courses/hugo-theme-minima-gisma into the Hugo theme field activate Open in new session Click on Create Project  After some seconds you will see the new website project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting startet with LiDAR</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-getting-startet-with-lidar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-getting-startet-with-lidar/</guid>
      <description>LiDAR data and LAS data format Technically spoken the LiDAR data comes in the LAS file format (for a format definition i.e. have a look at the American Society for Photogrammetry &amp;amp; Remote Sensing LAS documentation file). One LAS data set typically but not necessarily covers an area of 1 km by 1 km. Since the point clouds in the LAS data sets are large, a spatial index file (LAX) considerably reduces search and select operations in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Information from LiDAR data</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-20-forest-information-from-lidar-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-20-forest-information-from-lidar-data/</guid>
      <description>How to get started? For this first example we take a typical situation:
 we have no idea about the software and possible solutions we have no idea about LiDAR data processing and analysis we just google something like lidR package tutorial  Among the top ten is The lidR package book . So let’s follow the white rabbit…
Creating a Canopy Height Model (CHM) reloaded After successful application of the tutorial we will transfer it into a suitable script for our workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aGIS Ressources</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-agis-ressourcen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-agis-ressourcen/</guid>
      <description>Data, Readings and more Forest related ressources  del Río, M., Pretzsch, H., Alberdi, I. et al. Characterization of the structure, dynamics, and productivity of mixed-species stands: review and perspectives. Eur J Forest Res 135, 23–49 (2016). https://doi.org/10.1007/s10342-015-0927-6. (VPN necessary) Estimating Forest Structure Indices for Evalution of Forest Bird Habitats by an Airborne Laser-Scanner H. Hashimoto, J. Imanishi, A. Hagiwara, Y. Morimoto, K. Kitada Conference Paper Barnes, C.; Balzter, H.; Barrett, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a project-oriented workflow - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-setting-up-a-project-oriented-workflow-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-setting-up-a-project-oriented-workflow-part-1/</guid>
      <description>To set up a working or project environment, (normally) the first steps are defining different folder paths and loading the necessary R packages as well as additional functions.
If you also need to access additional software, like GIS, the appropriate binaries and software environments must be linked, too. Factoring in the major operating systems and the potentially multiple versions of software installed on a single system results in almost unlimited combinations of set ups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
