<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aGIS on gi-modules</title>
    <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/categories/agis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aGIS on gi-modules</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us^</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/categories/agis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project-Oriented Workflow</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-project-oriented-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-13-project-oriented-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Flexible but reproducible setup To set up a working or project environment, (normally) the first steps are defining different folder paths and loading the necessary R packages as well as additional functions.
If you also need to access additional software, like GIS, the appropriate binaries and software environments must be linked, too. Factoring in the major operating systems and the potentially multiple versions of software installed on a single system results in almost unlimited combinations of set ups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting startet with LiDAR</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-getting-startet-with-lidar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-getting-startet-with-lidar/</guid>
      <description>LiDAR data and LAS data format Technically spoken the LiDAR data comes in the LAS file format (for a format definition i.e. have a look at the American Society for Photogrammetry &amp;amp; Remote Sensing LAS documentation file). One LAS data set typically but not necessarily covers an area of 1 km by 1 km. Since the point clouds in the LAS data sets are large, a spatial index file (LAX) considerably reduces search and select operations in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Information from LiDAR data</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-20-forest-information-from-lidar-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-20-forest-information-from-lidar-data/</guid>
      <description>How to get started? For this first example we take a typical situation:
 we have no idea about the software and possible solutions we have no idea about LiDAR data processing and analysis we just google something like lidR package tutorial  Among the top ten is The lidR package book . So let’s follow the white rabbit…
Creating a Canopy Height Model (CHM) reloaded After successful application of the tutorial we will transfer it into a suitable script for our workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indices and More</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-23-indices-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-23-indices-and-more/</guid>
      <description>A few snippets to practice he following snippets fit in principle with the logic of the previous approach. They are adapted to tree level. However, we have already learned that we can also choose other aggregation concepts. Then they have to be adapted accordingly.
Above all, they show how sub-scaled satellite land use and LidAr data can be merged into one parameter set.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aGIS Ressources</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-agis-ressourcen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-agis-ressourcen/</guid>
      <description>Data, Readings and more Forest related ressources  del Río, M., Pretzsch, H., Alberdi, I. et al. Characterization of the structure, dynamics, and productivity of mixed-species stands: review and perspectives. Eur J Forest Res 135, 23–49 (2016). https://doi.org/10.1007/s10342-015-0927-6. (VPN necessary) Estimating Forest Structure Indices for Evalution of Forest Bird Habitats by an Airborne Laser-Scanner H. Hashimoto, J. Imanishi, A. Hagiwara, Y. Morimoto, K. Kitada Conference Paper Barnes, C.; Balzter, H.; Barrett, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic writing made easy</title>
      <link>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-making-of-academic-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gisma-courses.github.io/gi-modules/post/2021-11-16-making-of-academic-websites/</guid>
      <description>Setting up the blogdown Project We will use blogdown as an incredible easy to use an effiecient tool for setting up websites and producing content. First you need to install the neccessary packages:
# Install blogdown  install.packages(&amp;#34;blogdown&amp;#34;) # Install the &amp;#34;hugo&amp;#34; website framework blogdown::install_hugo(force = TRUE) library(blogdown) To initialize a blogdown website I strongly recommend to use the menu bar of RStudio.
 RStudio toolbar -&amp;gt; File -&amp;gt; New Project -&amp;gt; New Directory -&amp;gt; blogdown website Copy gisma-courses/hugo-theme-cleanwhite-gc into the Hugo theme field activate Open in new session Click on Create Project  After some seconds you will see the new website project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
